Alaska
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Alaska
2.1.3.2
Marist College
  Box 1515
- Alaska, 2.1.3.2
  - Alaska, circa 1950 - 1960s; 1 (Box 1515)
    - Lowell Thomas and Maynard Miller at camp 10 on the Juneau ice field, Alaska in July 1950, 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas and Maynard Miller at camp 10 on the Juneau ice field, Alaska in July 1950, 1-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas and 5 men in Alaska], 2
    - [Camp in Alaska], 3
    - [Two people on top of snowy hill in Alaska], 4
    - [Man sewing in Alaska], 5
    - [Man with skis taking a photograph in Alaska], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas on skis with two men in Alaska], 7
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 8
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 9
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 10
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 11
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 12
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 13
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 14
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 15
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 16
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 17
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 18
    - Lowell Thomas on skis with two others [12 images on same sheet], 19
  - Alaska [color photographs], circa 1970s; 2 (Box 1515)
    - LT and Wally Hickel, 1
    - Verso: LT and Wally Hickel, 1-verso
    - LT and Wally Hickel, 2
    - Verso: LT and Wally Hickel, 2-verso
    - LT and Wally Hickel, 3
    - Verso: LT and Wally Hickel, 3-verso
    - Alaska, 4
    - Verso: Alaska, 4-verso
    - Jan 1, 1975; Dear Lowell: Our happiest wishes to you for 1975! It has to be a great year for us all, and especially you. Certainly it will be for Sonny and Tay and family. They'll have the ski place in Juneau this summer - so it's time for your return to the high camps of JIPP. Let's count on it - say in late July - Affectionately, Mel, Joan, Ross and Lance; View East across the Juneau ice field; M. M. Miller, 5
    - Verso: Jan 1, 1975; Dear Lowell: Our happiest wishes to you for 1975! It has to be a great year for us all, and especially you. Certainly it will be for Sonny and Tay and family. They'll have the ski place in Juneau this summer - so it's time for your return to the high camps of JIPP. Let's count on it - say in late July - Affectionately, Mel, Joan, Ross and Lance; View East across the Juneau ice field; M. M. Miller, 5-verso
  - Alaska: Landscapes, circa 1950s - 1960s; 3 (Box 1515)
    - From Lowell Thomas's new all color thrilling adventure film "The Ice Men", 1
    - Verso: From Lowell Thomas's new all color thrilling adventure film "The Ice Men", 1-verso
    - [Alaska mountain and water landscape], 2
    - [Alaska mountain and water landscape], 3
    - [Alaska mountain and water landscape], 4
    - [Alaska mountain and water landscape], 5
    - [Alaska mountain and water landscape], 6
    - [Alaska mountain and water landscape], 7
    - From south Mt. McKinley 20,326'; Mac's Foto, 9455, 315 - 4th Ave., Anchorage, Alaska, 8
    - Verso: From south Mt. McKinley 20,326'; Mac's Foto, 9455, 315 - 4th Ave., Anchorage, Alaska, 8-verso
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series, circa 1915 - 1916; 4 (Box 1515)
    - The first day out at sea an officer on the "S.S. Jefferson" put a life preserver on all passengers who are not wise to the combination. I thought this picture was too good to pass up, 1
    - Verso: The first day out at sea an officer on the "S.S. Jefferson" put a life preserver on all passengers who are not wise to the combination. I thought this picture was too good to pass up, 1-verso
    - Alaskan streams abound with fish of all kinds in such great profusion it hardly can be called a sport to catch them, 2
    - Verso: Alaskan streams abound with fish of all kinds in such great profusion it hardly can be called a sport to catch them, 2-verso
    - Beardsley trout, cut throat trout, crescenti trout, 3
    - Verso: Beardsley trout, cut throat trout, crescenti trout, 3-verso
    - Caption: Midnight sun, Alaska, 4
    - Caption: Midnight sun at Fort Yukon, Alaska, 5
    - [Alaska mountain and water scene], 6
    - A typical Alaskan roadhouse on Fairbanks-Valdez trail. $2.50 per meal. By L. J. Thomas, 7
    - Verso: A typical Alaskan roadhouse on Fairbanks-Valdez trail. $2.50 per meal. By L. J. Thomas, 7-verso
    - [McClusky's Roadhouse in Alaska], 8
    - One of the farthest north clubhouses in the world, the home of the Dawson American Athletic Association. It contains club rooms, ball room, curling rinks, moving picture show, and hockey rink and has 10,000 feet of floor space. C. A. Creamer, former advance man for Barnum & Bailey has been at the head of it for 17 years, 9
    - Verso: One of the farthest north clubhouses in the world, the home of the Dawson American Athletic Association. It contains club rooms, ball room, curling rinks, moving picture show, and hockey rink and has 10,000 feet of floor space. C. A. Creamer, former advance man for Barnum & Bailey has been at the head of it for 17 years, 9-verso
    - Many women in the interior of Alaska dress like men. They wear head nets in the summer to protect them from the mosquitoes, 10
    - Verso: Many women in the interior of Alaska dress like men. They wear head nets in the summer to protect them from the mosquitoes, 10-verso
    - Field of cabbage near arctic circle. By L. J. Thomas, 11
    - Verso: Field of cabbage near arctic circle. By L. J. Thomas, 11-verso
    - [Alaskan man dancing], 12
    - [Team of sled dogs in Alaska], 13
    - [Steamboat and passengers in Alaska], 14
    - [Man and baby moose in Alaska], 15
    - [Building in Alaska], 16
    - Horse pulling man in cart in Alaska], 17
    - [Little waterfall in Alaska], 18
    - [Alaskan mountains], 19
    - [Log cabin with moose antlers in Alaska], 20
    - [7 people standing on a dock in Alaska], 21
    - [2 men talking on a boat in Alaska], 22
    - [3 little girls bundled up in Alaska], 23
    - [2 men in a boat in Alaska], 24
    - Caption: Leonhard Seppala and his "Siberians," winning the eighth all Alaska sweepstakes, Nome, Alaska, April 17th, 1915. Distance: 408 miles - Time: 78 hours, 44 mi. 57 sec., 25
    - [3 men in Alaska], 26
    - Lord Bishop Stringer of Yukon Territory welcoming "midnight summers." Picture by L. J. Thomas, 27
    - Verso: Lord Bishop Stringer of Yukon Territory welcoming "midnight summers." Picture by L. J. Thomas, 27-verso
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series, circa 1915 - 1916; 5 (Box 1515)
    - Note: The enclosed two pictures were taken on the way to Atlin. This reflection is of a mountain on the shore of Taku Inlet one mile from Indian Point and about ten miles from Lake Atlin. Several people I have shown the reflection picture to have declared it a fake. They couldn't believe it possible to get such a perfect reflection, but they were wrong. I have another that is even more beautiful which I will send you as soon as I get a print of it. On this picture I have been unable to decide which part is the reflection and which isn't but I believe the lighter half is not the mirrored part because the detail of the trees seems a trifle plainer [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 1
    - [Alaskan landscape], 2
    - [Boat in Alaska], 3
    - Note: The launch picture was taken on the lake [Lake Atlin] itself. The launch was made by hand, by an old Swiss jeweler, who worked on it in his spare hours for several years [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan] [from larger note], 4
    - [Flowing River in Alaska], 5
    - [People walking off a boat in Alaska], 6
    - [Steam-powered machine in Alaska], 7
    - [Man in a field in Alaska], 8
    - [Man with a dog in Alaska], 9
    - [Man with a dog in Alaska], 10
    - [Man with a dog in Alaska], 11
    - [7 men standing outside a building in Alaska], 12
    - [Young girl standing in a garden in Alaska], 13
    - Postcard, 14
    - [Man standing on an iceberg in Alaska], 15
    - [Klondike Brewery: The O'Biren Brewing & Malting Co.], 16
    - [Docking pier in Alaska], 17
    - [Running water in Alaska], 18
    - [Two men untangling rope in Alaska], 19
    - [Building on the water in Alaska], 20
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series - Alaska and Pacific Northwest, circa 1915 - 1916; 6 (Box 1515)
    - [Man standing in front of boat in Alaska], 1
    - [Northern Commerical Co. in Alaska], 2
    - [Alaskan landscape], 3
    - [Family sitting on a boat in Alaska], 4
    - [Boats in Alaska], 5
    - [Tee-pee in Alaska], 6
    - [Alaskan waterfront], 7
    - [Alaskan mountain landscape], 8
    - [Two men in boat in Alaska], 9
    - [Log cabin in Alaska], 10
    - [People gathering in Alaska], 11
    - [Man in front of log cabin with four dogs in Alaska], 12
    - [6 people in Alaska], 13
    - [Small town (?) in Alaska], 14
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series - Fairbanks, Alaska, circa 1915 - 1916; 7 (Box 1515)
    - [Crowd gathering outside N.C. Co. in Alaska], 1
    - [Group of men outside a building in Alaska], 2
    - [4 men outside Wells Fargo & Co. Express in Alaska], 3
    - [Man standing outside building in Alaska], 4
    - [Mother and child waiting by the road in Alaska], 5
    - [Woman and a weaving loom(?) in Alaska], 6
    - [Woman in canoe in Alaska], 7
    - [Home in Alaska], 8
    - [Neighborhood (?) in Alaska], 9
    - [Homes in Alaska], 10
    - [Man with a tin basin in Alaska], 11
    - [Man standing in garden in Alaska], 12
    - [Field in Alaska], 13
    - [Man picking flowers in Alaska], 14
    - [Grassy hill in Alaska], 15
    - [Alaskan farm], 16
    - [Farm in Alaska], 17
    - [Bushels of corn husks on an Alaskan farm], 18
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series - Fairbanks, Alaska (mining), circa 1915 - 1916; 8 (Box 1515)
    - [Man and 3 women in Alaska], 1
    - [Work zone in Alaska (?)], 2
    - [Building in Alaska], 3
    - [Building with steam pipes in Alaska], 4
  - Leather trunk series - Fort Seward, 1916; 9 (Box 1515)
    - Note: Letter describing pictures, 1
    - The two enclosed pictures are of snapshots I took on my first visit to Haines and Fort Seward, June 26th [1916]. The one of the soldiers drilling was taken on the parade ground at the Fort with Portage Bay in the back ground. Two companies are stationed at this post with a total enrollment of about 200 men. The building to the right is the hospital, to the left the barracks of Company C. in between are some of the residences of married non-commissioned officers and extending out in the bay is the Fort dock with the "Peterson" tied along side [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 2
    - Verso: description from letter describing series, 2-verso
    - [Fort Seward], 3
    - Fort Seward, 4
    - Verso: Fort Seward, 4-verso
    - [Fort Seward], 5
    - [Fort Seward], 6
    - Major McAndrew's wife on the S.S. Peterson, 7
    - Verso: Major McAndrew's wife on the S.S. Peterson, 7-verso
    - The morning of the Fourth [July 1916] I went down with a crowd from Skagway to get a few feet of film on the baseball game between the soldiers and the Indians, the canoe race, the tug of war, the greased pole contest, the obstacle race, the sprints between the natives and the track men from the Fort and the gas-boat race [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 8
    - Verso: description from letter describing series, 8-verso
    - The morning of the Fourth [July 1916] I went down with a crowd from Skagway to get a few feet of film on the baseball game between the soldiers and the Indians, the canoe race, the tug of war, the greased pole contest, the obstacle race, the sprints between the natives and the track men from the Fort and the gas-boat race [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 9
    - Verso: description from letter describing series, 9-verso
    - The morning of the Fourth [July 1916] I went down with a crowd from Skagway to get a few feet of film on the baseball game between the soldiers and the Indians, the canoe race, the tug of war, the greased pole contest, the obstacle race, the sprints between the natives and the track men from the Fort and the gas-boat race [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 10
    - Verso: description from letter describing series, 10-verso
    - The morning of the Fourth [July 1916] I went down with a crowd from Skagway to get a few feet of film on the baseball game between the soldiers and the Indians, the canoe race, the tug of war, the greased pole contest, the obstacle race, the sprints between natives and the track men from the Fort and the gas-boat race [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 11
    - Verso: description from letter describing series, 11-verso
    - The morning of the Fourth [July 1916] I went down with a crowd from Skagway to get a few feet of film on the baseball game between the soldiers and the Indians, the canoe race, the tug of war, the greased pole contest, the obstacle race, the sprints between natives and the track men from the Fort and the gas-boat race [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 12
    - Verso: description from letter describing series, 12-verso
    - This other snapshot is of an old prospector on his way back to the creeks after laying in a few week's supplies. Although a bachelor, who has lived for the past ten years out in the wilderness all alone, barely panning enough colors to pay for his grub, he seems to get a lot of joy out of life and rides along the mountain roads strumming on his guitar and singing as though he had the whole world by the horns [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 13
    - Verso: description from letter describing series, 13-verso
    - [no description], 14
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series - friends of Lowell Thomas, circa 1915 - 1916; 10 (Box 1515)
    - Grave of an Indian chief, at Wrangell. The two totems represent the "killer" whale, which was the animal of chieftan's family. One of the girls is a stenog[grapher] from Portland and the one in the white hat and dress lives up near the Arctic Circle at Ruby. Their companions are the "Edelweiss twins," Edward and George Seippel [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 1
    - Verso: Grave of an Indian chief, at Wrangell. The two totems represent the "killer" whale, which was the animal of chieftan's family. One of the girls is a stenog[grapher] from Portland and the one in the white hat and dress lives up near the Arctic Circle at Ruby. Their companions are the "Edelweiss twins," Edward and George Seippel [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 1-verso
    - Prof. Gorgeson, of Sitka, Alaskan agricultural expert and his wife who were on the "Jefferson" coming up. They want us to visit them next summer and sample the largest strawberries in the world which are grown by the U.S. experiment station there [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 2
    - Verso: Prof. Gorgeson, of Sitka, Alaskan agricultural expert and his wife who were on the "Jefferson" coming up. They want us to visit them next summer and sample the largest strawberries in the world which are grown by the U.S. experiment station there [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 2-verso
    - One of the Edelweiss twins took this picture the day we hiked up the mountain at George's Inlet cannery. It was about 30 minutes later that I fell off the log I wrote you about sometime ago. These girls are stenographers for a Portland canning company. They claimed the Edelweiss brothers and me as their private property before the boat left Seattle [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 3
    - Verso: One of the Edelweiss twins took this picture the day we hiked up the mountain at George's Inlet cannery. It was about 30 minutes later that I fell off the log I wrote you about sometime ago. These girls are stenographers for a Portland canning company. They claimed the Edelweiss brothers and me as their private property before the boat left Seattle [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan], 3-verso
    - [Woman standing on dock in Alaska], 4
    - [Woman on Boat in Alaska], 5
    - [Man and woman dancing on boat in Alaska], 6
    - [Family on boat in Alaska], 7
    - [Woman and bear in Alaska], 8
    - [People playing with bear in Alaska], 9
    - [Two people standing near log cabins in Alaska], 10
    - [Woman standing near animal skins in Alaska], 11
    - [Makeshitf tent in Alaska], 12
    - [Man holding up two animal skins in Alaska], 13
    - [Small group of people in Alaska], 14
    - [Community of people in Alaska], 15
    - [Group of people in Alaska], 16
    - [Gathering of people in Alaska], 17
    - [Group of men in Alaska], 18
    - [Group of people in Alaska], 19
    - [Group of people in Alaska], 20
    - [3 men talking in Alask], 21
    - [Two men on a boat (?) in Alaska], 22
    - [Two men talking in Alaska], 23
    - [Man standing in front of a boat in Alaska], 24
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series - glaciers, circa 1915 - 1916; 11 (Box 1515)
    - Taku glacier, 4 P.M.; taken from the hurricane deck of the S.S. Jefferson with the S.S. Prince Rupert in the distance, 1
    - Verso: Taku glacier, 4 P.M.; taken from the hurricane deck of the S.S. Jefferson with the S.S. Prince Rupert in the distance, 1-verso
    - [Taku glacier], 2
    - [Glaciers in Alaska], 3
    - [Ship in Alaska], 4
    - [View of mountains from a boat in Alaska], 5
    - [Bridge in Alaska], 6
    - [Alaskan mountain landscape], 7
    - [Alaskan glaciers], 8
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series - mines, circa 1915 - 1916; 12 (Box 1515)
    - Hydralic mining at Iditarod, Alaska, on the Innoko River, 1
    - Verso: Hydralic mining at Iditarod, Alaska, on the Innoko River, 1-verso
    - [Alaskan river], 2
    - [Boat sailing in Alaska], 3
    - [Boat on Alaskan river], 4
    - [People by a rock wall in Alaska], 5
    - [Building being built in Alaska], 6
    - [Building being built in Alaska], 7
    - [Two men working on a building], 8
    - [Two men working on a building], 9
    - [Machine (?) in Alaska], 10
    - [Machine (?) in Alaska], 11
    - [Six black foxes], 12
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series - mountaineers, 1916; 13 (Box 1515)
    - Note: [letter from Lowell Thomas to Frances Ryan], [PDF], 1
    - (The President of the Alaskan Mountaineers, hunting mountain goats among the glaciers and the crags of Chilkat mountains), 2
    - The President of the Alaskan Mountaineers, hunting mountain goats among the glaciers and the crags of Chilkat mountains. Whoope-e-e-e!!, 3
    - Verso: The President of the Alaskan Mountaineers, hunting mountain goats among the glaciers and the crags of Chilkat mountains. Whoope-e-e-e!!, 3-verso
    - The enclosed snapshot taken of four "Alaskan Mountaineers" ascending a snowbank on the way to the summit of the "A.B.," back of Skagway, is another in which the camera was tipped so that the perpendicularity of the grade was lost. It looks as though we were on an almost level stretch of snow but it really was so steep we had to sink our toes in several inches at each step to keep from taking a mile-a-minute ride to the bottom of the mountain [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan] [descrption an except from letter], 4
    - Gastineau channel near Thane, Alaska. S.S. Prince Rupert with Juneau, Alaska, to the left 1 mile away. {The other is a snapshot of Taku glacier with the S.S. Prince Rupert of the Grand Trunk Pacific line directly in front of it. This picture was taken at 4 o'clock in the morning while it was still twilight [photograph accompanied by a letter to Frances Ryan]}, 5
    - Verso1: Gastineau channel near Thane, Alaska. S.S. Prince Rupert with Juneau, Alaska, to the left 1 mile away., 5-verso
    - Notice the look on the face of the man below. Mr. Cole's hobnailed boots were making raw beefsteak out of my shoulder and we were on a ledge only a few inches wide with a 300 foot drop directly underneath. This picture, like all but one of the others we took that day, fails to show how steep the mt. was, 6
    - Verso: Notice the look on the face of the man below. Mr. Cole's hobnailed boots were making raw beefsteak out of my shoulder and we were on a ledge only a few inches wide with a 300 foot drop directly underneath. This picture, like all but one of the others we took that day, fails to show how steep the mt. was, 6-verso
    - By the time we got to the summit of "A.B.," mountain all the fellows were perspiring like a man fireing [sic] an engine on the "Cape to Cairo" railroad crossing the equator. This is a picture of one of the gang posing as Lady Godiva. The water in the distance is Lynn Canal. Unfortunately it was a hazy day or the picture would show the canal for 50 miles, 7
    - Verso: By the time we got to the summit of "A.B.," mountain all the fellows were perspiring like a man fireing [sic] an engine on the "Cape to Cairo" railroad crossing the equator. This is a picture of one of the gang posing as Lady Godiva. The water in the distance is Lynn Canal. Unfortunately it was a hazy day or the picture would show the canal for 50 miles, 7-verso
    - [Man on top of mountain in Alaska], 8
    - [Man on top of mountain in Alaska], 9
    - If you like to scale cliffs I'll give you all your heart desires next summer. How do you like this picture, 10
    - Verso: If you like to scale cliffs I'll give you all your heart desires next summer. How do you like this picture, 10-verso
    - [Man climbing ciff in Alaska], 11
    - [Man climbing cliff in Alaska], 12
    - [Man climbing cliff in Alaska], 13
    - [Man climbing cliff in Alaska], 14
    - [Man repelling from cliff in Alaska], 15
    - [Man repelling from cliff in Alaska], 16
    - [Man on top of mountain in Alaska], 17
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series - native peoples, circa 1915 - 1916; 14 (Box 1515)
    - Chilkat Indian chief and his bride in Sioux costume showing their similarity to other American Indians. The Chilkats are a branch of the Thlingets who are famous for their totem poles, 1
    - Verso: Chilkat Indian chief and his bride in Sioux costume showing their similarity to other American Indians. The Chilkats are a branch of the Thlingets who are famous for their totem poles, 1-verso
    - Chief Isaac, Head of the Moosehide Tribe of Indians near Dawson City on the Yukon, 2
    - Verso: Chief Isaac, Head of the Moosehide Tribe of Indians near Dawson City on the Yukon, 2-verso
    - King Island Eskimo who live on an island midway between Alaska and Bering Sea, 3
    - Verso: King Island Eskimo who live on an island midway between Alaska and Bering Sea, 3-verso
    - Eskimo and their Kyaks [sic] in Kotzebue Sound near Arctic Ocean, 4
    - Verso: Eskimo and their Kyaks [sic] in Kotzebue Sound near Arctic Ocean, 4-verso
    - [Eskimos in their Kayaks in Kotzebue Sound neat Arctic Ocean], 5
    - [Four boats tied to shore in Alaska], 6
    - [Native Alaskan man], 7
    - [Nets hanging in Alaska], 8
    - [Fishing nets hanging in Alaska], 9
    - [Waterfront in Alaska], 10
    - [Waterfront landscape in Alaska], 11
    - [Waterfront landscape in Alaska], 12
    - [Waterfront scene in Alaska], 13
    - [Boats and a tent on an Alaskan waterfront], 14
    - [Log cabins on an Alaskan waterfront], 15
    - [House on waterfront in Alaska], 16
    - [House on waterfront in Alaska], 17
    - [Log cabin on waterfront in Alaska], 18
    - [Log cabin in the woods of Alaska], 19
    - [Tents pitched in Alaska], 20
  - Alaska: Leather trunk series - native peoples, circa 1915 - 1916; 15 (Box 1515)
    - [A group of natives in Alaska], 1
    - [The Polato Coffee House in Alaska], 2